Hi. I'm Rebecca from engVid.
In this lesson, I'll show you an
advanced way to improve your English.
Let me start by asking
you a few questions.
Do you cut your own hair?
Do you repair your own car?
Do you fix your roof?
If you're like most people, you probably
do not do those things by yourself;
you have someone else do
those things for you. Right?
So in English, when you have someone else
perform an action for you, we express that
in a different way, and that's what you're
going to learn in this lesson. Okay? Let's
have a look at the board.
Okay, so let's say that you do something by
yourself. Okay? Then you would say, for example:
"I paint the house every year."
That's if you do it by yourself.
If you... In the
past, we would say:
"I painted the house last year."
In the future, you would say:
"I will paint the house
next year." Right?
That's when you do the action.
That's the normal way in which
we construct an
English sentence.
But what if you don't do it yourself? What
if somebody else comes in and does it for
you? Okay? You hire a painter, and he or she
does the work for you. Then, in English, we
have to express it in a different way.
We have to express it like this.
In the present, it would be:
"I have the house
painted every year."
So what's special, there? This:
"I have the house
painted every year."
Last year or in the past:
"I had the house painted
last year." Okay?
See the difference, there? And when
we're talking about the future:
"I will have the house
painted next year." Okay?
Good.
Now, I know that sounds like a mouthful. That
means it sounds like a lot of words, and it
is a lot of words in the beginning until you
understand how it's constructed, but just
try to see the difference between: "I paint
the house." and "I have the house painted.",
between: "I painted the house."
and "I had the house painted.",
between: "I will paint the house."
and "I will have the house painted."
Okay? That's what you
have to do when you
are talking about something which someone
else does for you; a service which someone
else performs for you. Okay?
Let's look at a few more examples, and then
you'll understand a little better. So let's
say, for example, I don't cut my own hair, and
I guess you don't cut your own hair either.
So, how would you say that? Okay? If somebody
else does it for you? You would say:
"I have my hair cut every
month." for example.
In the past: "I had my hair
cut." Sorry, it should
be "last month". Okay. And:
"I will have my hair
cut next month." Okay?
So we have present, past, future.
So what was special, there?
"I have my hair cut",
"I had my hair cut",
"I will have my hair cut".
Okay? So that's the way we
express it when a hairdresser or
someone else, or a barber, is going
to cut your hair, and not you.
Okay, next. Now, here we're going to talk
about John. John is a rich guy, and he's also
doing very well, he makes a lot of money,
but he doesn't like to clean. So he doesn't
clean his own apartment. He calls a maid in to
clean his apartment. So, when we're talking
about John, we say... We don't
say: "John cleans his apartment",
because he doesn't do it himself; someone
else does it for him. Right? So we say:
"John has his apartment
cleaned every week."
Okay. I said he's rich.
Okay, he has the money.
"John had his apartment
cleaned last week."
Or:
"John will have his apartment
cleaned next week."
Same construction:
"has his apartment cleaned",
"had his apartment cleaned",
"will have his
apartment cleaned".
Okay? Same concept in
every single example.
Let's take one last example. So, let's say
a hotel-right?-they have many floors, they
have to wash their windows regularly. But they
don't do it themselves; they hire a company
to do that, a window-washing company.
So we could say:
"The hotel has its windows
washed every year." Right?
Last year, we're talking
about the past:
"The hotel had its windows
washed last year."
Here we go. And future:
"The hotel will have its
windows washed next year."
Okay? All right.
So, you have just learned a really important
advanced-level point in English grammar.
I hope you've caught it. I'm sure you'd like
to do a little more practice on that, which
would be a very good idea.
For that,
go to our website:
www.engvid.com.
There you can do a quiz on this and really master
it, because it's quite a big difference. Right?
We don't say: "I cut my hair."
We say: "I have my hair cut."
And these kind of small changes will
improve your English tremendously.
For more tips like that
on improving your English
quickly and effectively,
subscribe to my YouTube channel so
you can get regular videos. Okay?
Thanks for watching.
Bye for now.